# Matthew Spaulding

#### Full Stack Developer

• CLEARWATER, 33761, UNITED STATES

# Profile

Full Stack Developer with over eight years of experience. Proven success in building software applications from conception to completion. Mentors and peer reviews junior developers. Active member of the development community, contributing to open source on GitHub with a Stack Overflow reputation of over 6000.

# Employment history

# Angular Developer at iProcedures, Tampa

March 2016 - Present

- Built a cloud-based mobile Anesthesia Information Management System (AIMS).
- Developed a real-time vitals monitor using the D3.js charting library.
- · Created Windows and Mac desktop applications using Electron.
- · Automated versioning and deployment system to deliver updates to clients.
- Peer reviewed junior developers using the Gitflow workflow.

#### .Net C# AngularJS Web Developer at Toptal, Tampa

September 2015 - March 2016

Bubble's University

- A children's learning platform.
- https://bubblesu.com

Herndonwood Associates

- Created ReKoN, a risk management platform for banking institutions.
- Implemented Azure as the cloud server and storage solution.
- · Created a multi-level role system.

# .Net Web API Developer at Wolters Kluwer Law & Business, Tampa January 2014 - September 2015

- Developed a medical coding suite.
- Built a tool that uses fuzzy logic to find ICD10 codes based on search terms.
- Built in the Azure cloud.

## Windows 8 Developer at Mad Mobile, Tampa

November 2012 - October 2013

Office Depot Windows Store App

- Created an eCommerce Windows app for a major online retailer.
- Connected to a custom API developed by Office Depot.
- Allowed users to see special deals, read product reviews, and add items to their cart.
- Displayed closest store by using geolocation.

#### Mad Dash

- Developed Mad Mobile's custom mobile specific content management system.
- Gave clients a dashboard to control their mobile images, menus, and content.

#### Details

2584 Brandywine Dr, Clearwater, 33761, United States 727-324-8369 mail@mattspaulding.org

NATIONALITY

US Citizen

#### Social Profiles

MattSpaulding.org

Github

Stack Overflow

**Hacker Rank** 

#### Skills

Mongo

**Express** 

Angular

Node

Typescript

Javascript

C#

HTML5

SCSS

.Net

Web API

**Entity Framework** 

Bootstrap

Material Design

Electron

#### Hobbies

Ping Pong Foosball Chess

#### .Net MVC4 Developer at Agile Thought, Tampa

August 2012 - November 2012

• Built risk analysis software for Price Waterhouse Cooper

#### .Net Mobile Web Developer at Mad Mobile, Tampa

December 2011 - August 2012

- Converted several eCommerce websites into mCommerce mobile websites.
- Scraped HTML from the websites and presented the data as JSON through a RESTful .Net Web API.
- Architected an extensible application core used as the base for all of the mobile sites.

### Adobe Flex Developer at Enporion, Tampa

January 2011 - December 2011

• Developed an online reverse auction website for municipality utilities.

## Basic Developer at Raytheon, Largo

May 2009 - July 2010

- Developed a tool to automate calibration of electrical equipment in Basic.
  (Voltameter, oscilloscope, etc.)
- The tool shrunk a 6 hour calibration process down to ten minutes.

# Education

Master of Science in Computer Engineering, University of South Florida, Tampa

2011

GPA: 3.25

Eta Kappa Nu Honor Society President

# Publications

# Build Ultra-Modern Web Apps with Angular Material 2016

Material Design uses a paper metaphor, bold intentions, and meaningful motion to give user interfaces an ultra-modern feel. Web applications built using AngularJS can now easily adopt these design principles using Angular Material, a reference implementation of Google's Material Design Specification.

http://www.toptal.com/angular-js/ultra-modern-web-apps-angular-material

# A Dynamic Hierarchical Web-Based Portal (Master Thesis) 2011

A dynamic hierarchical web-based portal was created to house a suite of web-based supply chain management applications. The portal was designed in a hierarchical manner to match the structure of large companies. Administrators of the portal have the ability to form the portal in such a way to mimic the existing structure of their company.

# Personal Projects

#### FreeStock

- A collection of bots that manage your stock portfolio.
- Stock picks based on historical trend analysis.
- https://FreeStock.market

### Angular Material Kitchen Sink, Deprecated

- Everything Angular Material... everything but the kitchen sink.
- An open-source AngularJS project, Angular Material is the reference implementation of Google's Material Design Specification. This project provides a fully-functioning AngularJS project showcasing UI components based on Material Design.

# Blrbr, Deprecated

- Push-to-talk for Twitter.
- An iPhone and Android mobile app that turns your phone into a social Walkie-Talkie.

# I'd Cap That!, Deprecated

- Picture. Captioning. Mayhem.
- Strangers write captions on your pictures.

# Cuddle Bear, Deprecated

- A game for XBOX 360.
- A troubled teddy bear wreaks havoc on the town. Only on Xbox LIVE.